- Mr Silverstein?   - Yes. Who are you?
- Silverstein 先生吗?  - 是, 你是谁?
Anne Travers. Is my father here?
Anne Travers．我父亲在这里吗?
Yes, he's here. Come and see him and take him away.
是的, 他在这儿．来看一下, 把他带走吧
He's a fool. An old fool!
他糊涂了, 老糊涂了
Father?
父亲？
Father...
父亲...
Anne...
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
- 你在这里做什么？   - 找你啊
You were supposed to be meeting me.
你原本应该去接我
- Was I?   - At the airport.
- 是吗？    - 在机场
Father, what is the matter? You send me a cable saying you're in grave trouble.
父亲，是怎么回事？你给我发了电报，说你遇到大麻烦了
- And I fly half the way round the world...
- Trouble? Yes.
- 我飞了大半个地球...   - 麻烦? 是的
A great deal of trouble. It's that thing.
很大的麻烦．是那个东西
- The Yeti?   - Mm.
- 雪怪？      - 嗯
You're a stupid old fool, Julius Silverstein!
你是个愚蠢的糊涂蛋, Julius Silverstein！
ME the fool? You would like me to be the fool and give you back my Yeti, huh?
我是糊涂蛋？你就期望我是糊涂蛋, 好把雪怪还给你, 哈？
You must, man. Don't you understand? It's dangerous.
你必须, 伙计．你不明白吗？它太危险了
For 30 years this stands here in my museum, and now he tells me it is dangerous!
在我的博物馆放了３０年, 现在你跟我说它很危险！
- I wish I'd never brought it back from Tibet.
- Father, what has happened?
- 我期望我没有把它从西藏带回来   - 父亲, 发生了什么？
The silly old goat won't listen to me. I've told him, warned him.
这头老笨山羊不听我的．我告诉他了, 警告他了
- Damn it, he knows it's a robot!
- But, Father, the Yeti isn't dangerous.
- 蛋, 他知道它是个机器人   - 但是, 父亲, 雪怪并不危险
It can't work unless it has a control unit.
没有那个控制器它是不会启动的
But I've done it, Anne!
但我搞定了, Anne！
I HAVE reactivated the control unit.
我已经重新激活了控制器
But, Father, this is wonderful news.
啊, 父亲, 这是非常好的消息啊
Is it? Yes, I suppose it would be, except for one thing.
是吗？是, 我也觉得是, 除了一件事
What?
什么？
The sphere - it's gone!
那个球  - 不见了！
It's disappeared! You must let me have the Yeti back, Julius.
它消失了！你必须得让我把雪怪要回来, Julius
Make him understand, Anne!
你跟他说明白吧, Anne!
I understand.
我很明白
I buy the Yeti off you 30 years ago.
我30年前从你手里买走了雪怪
Now, it is valuable.
现在, 它值钱了
You try to scare me, take your Yeti back.
你就试图吓唬我, 好把你的雪怪要回去
Why? Money! You want to rob me!
为什么？钱！你想打劫我！
I'll buy the thing back if that's what you want!
我可以把它买回来, 如果你想要的是这个
No, no. It's priceless.
不, 不, 它是无价的
The only one in the world, and it is mine.
全世界独一无二的, 就我才有
- You fool!  - Thief!
- 你糊涂！    - 小偷！
- I'm not a thief.   - Swindler!
- 我不是小偷      - 骗子！
Stubborn old goat!
顽固的老山羊！
- Father!   - Take him away - out of my house!
- 父亲！   - 把他带走, 离开我的房子！
Father, perhaps you've made a mistake.
父亲，也许是你搞错了
You've put the sphere away somewhere in your laboratory and forgotten it.
你把那个球放在实验室里某个地方, 然后忘了
- You've done it before.
- No. I've looked everywhere.
- 你以前也干过这事   - 不, 我都找遍了
Let's go home and look again, shall we? You know what you're like.
我们回家去, 再找找, 行吗？你知道你是怎样的
Yes, but suppose...
好, 不过要是...
Let's go and have a quiet dinner, and you can tell me all about it.
走吧, 一起安静地用个晚餐, 你跟我详细说说
Then we'll go home and look for the sphere.
然后我们回家, 找那个球
Well, all right... But I warned you, Julius! I warned you!
好, 行吧...但我警告过你了, Julius! 我警告过你了
Get out! Take him away!
出去！把他带走！
Nobody destroys Julius Silverstein's collection! Nobody!
没谁能破坏 Julius Silverstein 的收藏品！没谁！
- Come on, Father.
- The Yeti's mine!
- 得啦, 父亲   - 雪怪是我的！
You can't scare me with your mad stories.
你别想用你的疯狂故事吓住我
Out! Out!
出去！出去！
Travers...
It is you? I am not frightened by your stupid tricks!
是你吗？我不会被你的愚蠢伎俩吓倒的
Travers! I know it's you.
Travers! 我知道是你
I'm not a fool!
我可不糊涂！
Agh!
啊！
(theme)
The Web of Fear
Doctor Who 1963 05x05 (whopix fan edit)
神秘博士老版 第五季第五集 恐惧之网 （粉丝剪辑版）
Some sort of grille.
某种栅栏
Don't say you've landed us in a prison!
可别说你降落到了一座监狱里！
It could be the dungeons of a castle.
可能是一座城堡的地牢
It's so dark.
好黑呀
Ah, steps.
啊, 台阶
Come along. Be careful.
过来, 小心点
Yes...
好...
It seems to be a large room.
看起来是个很大的房间
Tiled walls.
瓷砖墙
Curved ceiling.
拱形天花板
Come on.
快来
The floor seems to end here.
地面好像到这里就没有了
There's a sort of trench. Look.
这里有某种壕沟, 你看
- Hey, Doctor. Come and look at this.
- What have you found, Victoria?
- 嘿, 博士, 来看看这个   - 你发现了什么, Victoria？
See for yourself.
你自己看看
"Covent... Garden... "
"科文特...花园..."
（注：伦敦西部一街区名称, 特色是皇家歌剧院和诸多的小商店）
Yes, of course! It's an underground station. We're standing on the platform.
是了, 当然！这是一个地下车站, 我们站在月台上
- Underground station?   - Underground trains.
- 地下车站？   - 地铁
- A little after your time, Victoria.
- Is it always as dark as this?
- 略晚于你的时代, Victoria  - 总是这么黑吗？
No, it's probably the middle of the night. Come on. Let's go up top.
不．只是现在很可能是午夜．快来, 我们到顶上去
- Professor Travers is here, sir.
- Why have I been brought here? Who are you?
- Travers 教授来了, 先生  - 为什么带我来这儿？你是谁？
- Knight.       - Never heard of you.
- 我叫 Knight   - 从没听说过
Captain Knight. OK, Corporal.
Knight 上校。好了, 下士
It's no good shouting at me.
朝我喊可没什么好处
- I didn't ask for you.   - Who did, then?
- 不是我叫你来的   - 那是谁？
- Your daughter.   - Anne? Just like her mother.
- 你女儿   - Anne? 真像她妈
Always interfering in things she knows nothing about!
总是在她啥也不懂的事情上插手
I understood that you'd sent for her to come back from merica to help you.
我还以为是你把她从美国叫回来帮你的
What do you want me for, anyway?
你要我做什么？
I don't. I consider this to be a military matter./
不是我要。我认为这是一个军事问题
Well, you haven't much success so far, haven you?
那你到目前也还没获得什么成功, 是吧？
Army? What the devil do they know about it?
军方？他们到底对这个知道些什么？
- The Doctor was wrong!
- It's not night-time. It's broad daylight.
- 博士搞错了！   - 现在不是晚上, 是光天白日
- Just let me get my breath... Those stairs!
- It looks like we're locked in.
- 且让我喘口气...这些台阶！   - 看来我们被锁在里面了
- That's strange.  - Doctor...
- 这很奇怪啊     - 博士...
- Yes?    - Listen.
- 什么？   - 听
I can't hear anything.
我什么也没听到
Oh... It IS quiet. I see what you mean./
噢...是太安静了．我明白你的意思了
The middle of London. There should be some noise.
伦敦市中心, 应该会有些噪音才对
Hey, Doctor. There's an old man over there. Let's ask him.
嘿，博士，那儿有个老人, 我们去问问他
Yes, go on.
对, 去吧
Excuse me...
打扰一下...
Who are you?
你是谁？
- Harold Chorley. London Television.
- Oh, What?
- Harold Chorley. 伦敦电视台   - 噢，什么？
Television? Never watch it. Are you an actor or something?
电视台？从来没看过．你是个演员什么的吗？
Journalist, actually.
新闻记者, 实际上
The government decided to only allow one correspondent down here. The press chose me.
政府决定允许派一个新闻记者下来, 台里选了我
Oh, yeah?
噢, 那又怎样？
Tell me, Professor, will you be in charge of the scientific  ection, or will your daughter?
告诉我，教授，是你负责这里的科学组吗？还是你女儿
Mind your own business!
管好你自己的事！
And how long do you think it will take you to come up with the answer?
你觉得你需要多久才能得到答案？
- One week? Three, perhaps?
- How the hell should I know?
- 一周？三周, 也许要？  - 我怎么可能知道？
- Is that working?
- Of course.
- 那东西好使吗？   - 当然
It's more than likely we may not be able to defeat this menace.
感觉更像是, 我们可能无法消除这场危机
London...perhaps the whole of England might be completely wiped out. There - did you get that?
伦敦...也许整个英格兰都可能被完全毁灭．喏 - 你明白了吗？
- What are you doing, Doctor?
- Just confirming something.
- 你在干什么，博士？  - 只是确认点事情
Yes, just as I thought. There haven't been any trains here for some time.
是的，正如我所料, 这里有段时间没跑地铁了
What's that over there?
那边是什么？
It's a power cable. I wonder what it's doing down here.
是一根电缆．我很好奇它在这里有什么用
In there quickly!
进去那儿, 快！
Soldiers? I wonder what they're doing down here.
士兵？奇怪, 他们在这下面干什么？
- Let's go and ask them.
- No. I think we'd better tread carefully.
- 我们去问问他们   - 不, 我觉得我们还是小心行事
Let's go and find out what's going on first.
我们去看看是在干什么
What do you want us to do, Doctor?
你期望我们做什么, 博士？
You follow the soldiers, but keep out of sight.
你跟着那些士兵, 但别被看见了
I'm going to see where this cable goes to./
我要去看看这些线缆通向那里
Meet back here in a few minutes. Right?
过几分钟回来这里汇合。好吧？
- What's the matter?
- I thought I heard something.
- 怎么了？   - 我觉得我听到了点什么
- Getting a bit jumpy, aren't you, Weams?
- It's no wonder, is it, Staff?
- 有点神经质了吧, 是不, Weams?  - 那也不稀奇, 是吧, Staff?
- Shall we connect the new drum now, Staff?
- All right, Corporal.
- 我们现在要连上新桶了吧, Staff？  - 是, 下士
- Good thing we fixed these lights.
- Yeah. You said that again.
- 好的是我们把这些灯修好了  - 是，你说过了
- I can't hear anything.
- Are they still there?
- 我什么也听不见   - 他们还在那儿吗？
I think they must be moving. Come on.
我觉得他们肯定走了．快来
Agh!
啊！
I told you I heard something, didn't I?
我就说我听到了什么, 说过吧
Yeah. Come on!
是的。快来！
- I'm sorry!   - It was only a cobweb!
- 我很抱歉！   - 不过是蜘蛛网
- Do you think they heard?
- Hope not. Come on.
- 你觉得他们听到了吗？   - 但愿没有, 快来
Well, well, well, would you believe it? The Babes in the Wood!
好, 好, 好, 你能相信不？树林中的美女!
（备注：“树林中的美女”原为一童话故事名，后衍生为指在不知情的情况下进入危险境地的无辜者）
- You're quite sure there was nobody with you?
- How many more times?
- 你确定你们没有其他人？   - 还要说多少次？
That's all right, then.
那就没事了
- Clear to fire, Staff?
- Yes, they were on their own.
- 可以点火了吗, Staff?   - 是的, 就他们自己
Right.
好
What was all that about?
这都是怎么回事？
I suppose there's no harm in telling you. You two are very lucky.
我觉得告诉你也没有关系, 你们俩非常幸运
- We're going to blow up the tunnel.
- What?!
- 我们打算炸掉这个隧道   - 什么?!
- That's what the cable's for.
- The Doctor!
- 那些电缆是干这个的   - 博士！
It's all right. They were on their own. OK, let's not waste any more time. Off you go.
没问题了, 就他们自己．好, 我们不要再浪费时间, 走你
Agh!
啊